globalscholar.com 2013-03-22

# GlobalScholar: Privacy Policy

  * Home
  * Products 
  * Services 
  * We Support CCSS
  * About Us
  * Careers 

## **GlobalScholar Privacy Policy**

**Effective Date: September 16, 2007.**

GlobalScholar is committed to protecting your privacy and to handling your personal information with care and respect.

This Privacy Policy, which is part of and incorporated into the GlobalScholar Terms and Conditions of Use (“Terms”), describes how we collect, use, share and protect your personally identifiable information on the Site. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you expressly consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described below.

All capitalized terms that are not defined herein shall have the meanings ascribed to them in the Terms.

### Information Collection

We collect several types of personally identifiable information about our users:

### Information You Provide to Us

  * **Registration**.  You can browse our Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself.  But in order to purchase or teach Courses on the Site, you must first register and provide personally identifiable information (such as name, email address, password, birth date, preferred language, and time zone).  We may also collect other types of information which we may associate with personally identifiable information. If you apply to become an Instructor on the Site, you will be required to provide us with your social security number and/or taxpayer ID number.

  * **Purchase/Sale Transactions**.  If you purchase any Courses on the Site, our online purchase forms will request financial information (such as credit card number with expiration date and a billing address or bank account information).  We’ll note the type of services or products ordered or purchased, and the date of the order or purchase.

  * **Usage History, Interactive Features and Public Forums**.  We may also collect additional personal information when you use some features on the Site and when you correspond with our customer service representatives by phone, mail or e-mail.  If you use the interactive features or public forums (such as e-mail messaging) on the Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit in the body of your messages can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.  We reserve the right to terminate the Accounts of any registered users who use the GlobalScholar messaging system in a manner inconsistent with the Terms.

### Information Collected Through Technology

Our Site collects information through a variety of technical methods to create a “profile” of your preferences and for various purposes related to our business.  We collect information from your interaction with our Site, services, content and advertising, including computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, ad data, IP address and standard web log information.  We tie your personally identifiable information and your purchasing history to information in your profile, in order to provide tailored promotions and marketing offers and to improve the content of the Site for you.

The following methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf: 

  * **Cookies** We use “cookies” (small files placed on your hard drive) on certain pages to help analyze our web page flow; customize our services, content and advertising; identify you and maintain your signed-in status; measure promotional effectiveness; and promote trust and safety in the usage of the Site.  You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of our Site.  You may also encounter cookies from third parties on other websites accessible from our Site; we do not control such websites or their use of such cookies.

  * **Web Beacons.** We may employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons) that help us better manage content on our Site by informing us what content is effective. We tie the information gathered such technology to our users’ personally identifiable information.

  * **Log Files**. As is true of most websites, we automatically gather certain information (such as internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data) and store it in log files.  We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the Site, to track users’ movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may also link this data to personally identifiable information.

### Information That We Collect from Others

We may also occasionally supplement the personal information you submitted to us and the information we collected through technology with information from third party sources. 

### Use of Information

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience.  We may use your personal information to:

  * verify your eligibility to be a registered user (i.e. you are over the age of 13); 

  * verify permission granted to children (i.e., under the age of 13) to use the Site;

  * compare information for accuracy and verify it with third parties (such as performing background checks for users who wish to become Instructors and to offer a Course, who are not otherwise affiliated with a school district registered on our Site); 

  * provide the services and customer support you request; 

  * charge and collect bills, issue credits and debits, and disburse payments in connection with the transactions;

  * store all communications sent through the Site;

  * resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems; 

  * prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our Terms; 

  * customize, measure, and improve our services and the Site’s content and advertising; and

  * tell you about targeted marketing of products, service updates, special deals, and promotional offers as well as confirm the opening of any HTML-based emails to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and effectiveness of marketing campaigns based on the elections in your Account settings. 

We will also communicate with you by email in response to your inquiries, to provide any assistance you request, to manage your Account (such as billing and refund issues), and to send you strictly administrative, transaction or operation-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so (such as if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance or updates to the policies). Generally, you may not opt out of these non-promotional communications. But if you do not wish to receive these administrative, transaction or operation-related communications, you have the option to deactivate your Account by contacting Customer Support.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure Your Personal Information 

Personal information about our users is an important part of our business.  We are not in the business of selling or renting your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent.  

We may share your personal information (such as email address) with our corporate affiliates or corporate partners for their promotional uses unless you elect to “opt out.” If you do not “opt out” or if you consent to such sharing in the course of using a specific service or purchasing a particular Course, you authorize us to disclose your personal information to our corporate affiliates or selected corporate partners who may send marketing communications about their goods and services. If you are an Instructor, we will not share your social security number and/or taxpayer ID number (which you were required to provide as part of the application process to become an Instructor) with any third parties except as necessary to perform background checks with third party sources, to disburse funds for Courses you offer, or as otherwise noted below.

GlobalScholar has the right to share your personal information for the following purposes which are not subject to your “opt-out” choices: 

  * **Corporate Agents and Third Party Providers.**  We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf with respect to our business operations.  Examples include fraud investigations, providing customer service, processing credit card payments, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from user lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, and providing search results and links (including paid listings and links).  Except as separately permitted by other provisions in this Privacy Policy, these companies are allowed to gather, receive, and use your personal information only as needed to perform their functions or as required by law. 

  * **Authorized Third Parties**.  In certain circumstances, your dealings with a third party may have authorized that third party to obtain your personal information from GlobalScholar and to use that information in accordance with the third party’s own privacy practices and policies.  We will provide your information to such third parties only to the extent you explicitly authorized us to do so. 

  * **Parents**. We operate a “bright lights environment” on our Site.  If you are the Parent of a child under the age of 13 who created the child’s Account, we will share with you all messages and communications to and from your child that are sent through and stored in our system.

  * **Business Transitions.**  In the event GlobalScholar goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred as part of such transaction.  If we purchase a business, the personally identifiable information received with that business will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy if it is practicable and permissible to do so.  If we sell a business, we will include provisions in the selling contract requiring the purchaser to treat your personal information in the same manner required by the Privacy Policy effective at the time of closing.  You will be notified via a prominent notice on our Site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. 

  * **Legal Disclaimer**. In an effort to respect your privacy and our ability to keep the Site free from bad actors, we reserve the right to release your Account and other personal information when we believe such release is appropriate to: (a) comply with the law (including to meet our tax reporting obligations), or to respond to legal requirements (subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure served on GlobalScholar); (b) enforce or apply our Terms and other policies; and (c) protect the rights, property, or safety of GlobalScholar, our users, or others when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity (including exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection). In such events, we will disclose information relevant to the investigation, such as name, city, state, zip code, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, transactional history, and social security number and/or taxpayer ID number (if applicable). This does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from users for commercial purposes. 

### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We reserve the right to share aggregated demographic information about our user base (without linking to personally identifiable information about individual users) or de-personalized individual information (removal of name and other personally identifying characteristics) with our corporate affiliates and corporate partners.  Given the nature of this information, there are no restrictions under this Privacy Policy upon the right of GlobalScholar to aggregate or de-personalize your personal information. 

### Communication Preferences, Opt-In, and Opt-Out Choices

By accepting our Terms and Conditions your account will Opt-in to marketing e-mails. You have a choice to give or not to give us your consent to use your personal information for marketing purposes and to send you marketing e-mail. When you choose to “opt out,” you decline to give us your consent (a) to disclose your personal information with our corporate affiliates or corporate partners for their marketing purposes, and (b) to receive marketing communications or promotional materials via email from us, any corporate affiliates, or corporate partners. You can exercise and change your opt-out choices in the following way:

  * After registration, by accessing your Account settings, or by following the “unsubscribe” directions provided in the marketing email sent to you. 

If you choose to “opt out”, it may take up to ten (10) days after you “opt out” for your election to be fully effective. Our systems require time to update and promotional mailings using personal information shared before you elected to opt out may already be in process. Thus, your personal information might continue to be shared with our corporate affiliates and corporate partners and you might continue to receive promotional materials from GlobalScholar, our corporate affiliates and corporate partners for up to ten (10) business days after you have changed your opt-out election. 

### No Spam, Spyware or Spoofing

We and our users do not tolerate spam. Make sure to set your Communication Preferences for your Account so we communicate to you as you prefer.  You are not allowed to add any other Site user, even a user who has purchased a Course from you, to your mailing list (email or postal mail) without such user’s express consent.  To report Site-related spam or spoof emails to GlobalScholar, please forward the email to [customercare@GlobalScholar.com](mailto:customercare@GlobalScholar.com). 

You may not use our communication tools to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our Terms.  We reserve the right to automatically scan and manually filter messages to check for spam, viruses, phishing attacks and other malicious activity or illegal or prohibited content. 

### Security

The security and confidentiality of your personal information is extremely important to us. Your information is stored on our servers located in the United States.  We treat data as an asset that must be protected and use technical (i.e., Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software for encryption, passwords, physical security, etc.), administrative, and physical security measures to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure.  We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us during transmission and after we receive it. 

Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and impenetrable.  While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee, and you should not expect, absolute security. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. 

### Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information

You can see, review and change most of your personal information online through your account preferences. Generally, we cannot manually modify your personal information through any other means because it is very difficult to verify your identity remotely.  You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate.

### Deactivating Your GlobalScholar Account

You may deactivate your Account by contacting Customer Support. Upon your request, we will close your Account and remove your personal information and posted Course (if applicable) from the Site as soon as reasonably possible, based on your Account activity and in accordance with applicable law.  We do retain personal information from closed Accounts to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

### Links to Other Sites and Third Party Advertisers

Our Site may include third-party advertising and links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by GlobalScholar. 

To the extent these third parties are not our corporate partners, we do not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party websites or to advertisers and Internet advertising companies working on their behalf (also called “ad networks” or “network advertisers”).  These network advertisers sometimes use technology to send (or “serve”) their advertisements that appear on our Site directly to your browser.  They automatically receive your IP address when this happens.  They may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons, and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. 

When you click on an advertisement on our Site that links to a third party website or a network advertiser, then you are leaving our Site.  This Privacy Policy will not apply to your personally identifiable information collected on that third party’s website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third parties or network advertisers and you must read the privacy policy posted on their respective websites to see how your personally identifiable information will be handled. 

### Changes in this Privacy Policy

Please see our Terms for details on how we will provide notice of changes in this Privacy Policy.

### Your California Privacy Rights

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please send an e-mail or write us using the email or postal address listed under the Contact Us section. 

### Contact Us

To contact us with any questions, comments or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy or our Children’s Privacy Policy: 

By e-mail:

By mail:

GlobalScholar   
ATTN: Privacy  
1100 112th Ave NE  
Suite 100 South Bldg  
Bellevue, WA 98004 

By phone:  
1-877-824-4040

### Children’s Privacy Policy

The Children’s Privacy Policy is designed to describe GlobalScholar’s privacy policies and principles with respect to children under the age of 13. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) requires that we inform Parents about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children under 13 years of age and that we obtain the consent of Parents in order for such children to use certain features of our Site. 

### Collection of Personally Identifiable Information About Children

Children can surf on the Site and view content without giving any personal information to us.  But to use the services and participate in certain features available on the Site, children will need to be a registered user. Children under 13 years of age can only get a registered GlobalScholar account (“Account”) if their Parent creates one for them and provides verifiable consent. 

We also operate a “bright lights” environment; we will store all of the child’s emails and communications through the Site after his or her Account is activated. So during the registration, we give the Parent the option to stay involved after the child is signed up. If the Parent requests access to the child’s e-mails and activities on the Site, we will send him or her all the recorded communications and activities of the child on a weekly basis. 

Note that all sites that are directed to children under 13 are prohibited by law from conditioning a child’s participation in an online activity on the child’s providing more personal information than is reasonably necessary. If a Parent allows us to collect personal information about his or her child, we may also link certain Information Collected Through Technology to that personal information.  We do not entice children, by the prospect of a special game, prize, or other activity, to provide more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity.

### Use of Personally Identifiable Information About Children

We will use the personally identifiable information that we collected about the child to personalize our communications with the child regarding the Courses on the Site.  For example, if the child’s Account is associated with a particular school district registered on our Site, we will share that child’s Site activity information with that school district, which will use it solely for educational purposes, and we will send personalized communications to the child regarding the different Courses sponsored or provided by his or her particular school district on the Site. 

We will also use cookies to help to enhance and personalize your child’s experience with the Site. Cookies will be used to “remember” your child and his or her particular preferences to customize the child’s experience on the Site.  We may use anonymous information about the use of the Site for research purposes and to improve our Site.  We will not sell any information collected by cookies or use the information for commerce-related purposes.

### Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information About Children

As a matter of policy, we do not disclose personally identifiable information about children to third parties. 

There are, however, a few exceptions.  We may disclose such information about a child to school districts registered on our Site which are associated with the child’s Account, as noted above. We may also disclose such information to third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to: protect the security of integrity of our sites; to enforce our Terms and take precautions against liability; to respond to judicial process; or to the extent permitted under provisions of law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation related to public safety.  Additionally, in the event that all or substantially all of the assets relating to the Site are transferred or sold to another entity, personally identifiable information submitted to us may be transferred to the acquiring entity.

To protect the child’s personal information from disclosure to third parties while participating in certain interactive features of the Site, we have created some additional safeguards.  The child’s real e-mail address will never be publicly disclosed or used by us on the Site because each Account will have an alias GlobalScholar e-mail address that is linked to the child’s real email address so that all communications from other Site users will go through the Site, get recorded and forwarded to the child’s actual e-mail.  Only the child’s first name and first initial of the last name will be displayed while the child is logged on the Site. However, note that we have no control over what content children communicate through their alias e-mail addresses or certain areas of the Site. Therefore, Parents take full responsibility for monitoring such communications

### Notification and Obtaining Consent for Collection of Personally Identifiable Information

As part of the registration process when a Parent creates an Account for a child, we will provide notification by displaying this Children’s Privacy Policy (along with the Terms) in order to obtain his or her express consent to our collection of personally identifiable information from their children.

### Right to Access, Change or Delete Personally Identifiable Information About Children

Each Parent will have the option to view a transcript of all emails, discussions or content trail of the child’s activities on the Site as part of the “bright lights environment” that allows the Parent to monitor the child’s activities on the Site. 

Parents may review the personally identifiable information provided about their children, change how we use it, refuse to permit us to collect further personally identifiable information from their children, and request that the personally identifiable information we collected be deleted from our records or changed. Parents may contact our Customer Service department via e-mail at [customercare@GlobalScholar.com](mailto:customercare@GlobalScholar.com) to do so.  Please include the child’s email address in the e-mail so that we can better assist you with your inquiry or request.

### Notification of Changes to Children’s Privacy Policy

Please see our Terms for details on how we will provide notice of changes in the Privacy Policy, including the Children’s Privacy Policy. In addition to what is stated in the Terms, we will provide parents notice by e-mail of any material changes in the way we intend to collect, use, and/or share children’s personal information.  Please note that, at all times, parents should update their personal information to provide us current e-mail addresses.  We will apply material changes in our Children’s Privacy Policy only in conformance with applicable law, including any applicable provisions of COPPA that require parental consent.

**Turn Data into Action.** Call or click to discuss your needs and schedule a demo. 1-800-473-4572 or [Contact Us](http://learn.globalscholar.com/contactus.html)
